Guide to the George Washington University Publications collection, 1924-2017 RG0154
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Education Policy, Series 6
  - Private colleges: present conditions and future prospects by Carol Herrnstadt Shulman., 1974; Series 6; 54 pages; 23 cm. (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - College trustees: a question of legitimacy J.L. Zwingle and William V. Mayville; prepared by the ERIC Clearinghouse on Higher Education, the George Washington University, Washington, D.C., 1974; Series 6; 53 pages: forms; 23 cm. (Box 2, Folder 8)
    Includes bibliographical references (pages 33-37).; Also issued online.
  - Educational auditing and voluntary institutional accrediting Fred F. Harcleroad and Frank G. Dickey; prepared by the ERIC Clearinghouse on Higher Education, the George Washington University., 1975; Series 6; 35 pages; 23 cm. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    Includes bibliographical references (pages 32-35).
  - Academic credit for prior off-campus learning David A. Trivett; prepared by the ERIC Clearinghouse on Higher Education, the George Washington University., 1975; Series 6; 72 pages; 23 cm. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    Includes bibliographical references (pages 65-72).
  - Rational for Experiential Educational, 1975; Series 6 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Emerging sources of student influence by Samuel E. Kellams., 1975; Series 6; 55 pages; 23 cm. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    Prepared by the ERIC Clearinghouse on Higher Education.; Includes bibliographical references (pages 50-55).
  - Competency programs in higher education David A. Trivett; prepared by the ERIC Clearinghouse on Higher Education, the George Washington University., 1975; Series 6; 68 pages; 23 cm. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    Includes bibliographical references (pages 64-68).; Also available online from the ERIC website.
  - Conflict and collective bargaining David W. Leslie; prepared by the ERIC Clearinghouse on Higher Education., 1975; Series 6; 70 pages; 23 cm. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    Includes bibliographical references (pages 55-57).
  - Applying the goals of student financial aid Jonathan D. Fife; prepared by the ERIC Clearinghouse on Higher Education, George Washington University., 1975; Series 6; 67 pages; 23 cm. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    Includes bibliographical references (pages 55-67).
  - The implications of Federal education policy Clifton Conrad and Joseph Cosand; prepared by the ERIC Clearinghouse on Higher Education, the George Washington University, Washington, D.C., 1976; Series 6; 65 pages; 24 cm. (Box 2, Folder 10)
    Includes bibliographical references (pages 62-65).
  - Higher education and the economy Hans H. Jenny; prepared by the ERIC Clearinghouse on Higher Education., 1976; Series 6; 56 pages; 23 cm. (Box 2, Folder 10)
    Includes bibliographical references (pages 53-56).; Prepared pursuant to a contract with the National Institute of Education, U.S. Department of Health, Education and Welfare.
  - Private higher education and public funding by Louis T. Benezet; prepared by the ERIC Clearinghouse on Higher Education, the George Washington University., 1976; Series 6; 62 pages; 23 cm. (Box 2, Folder 10)
    Includes bibliographical references (pages 52-62).
  - Enrollment trends in higher education Carol Herrnstadt Shulman; prepared by the ERIC Clearinghouse on Higher Education, the George Washington University., 1976; Series 6; 45 pages; 23 cm. (Box 2, Folder 11)
    Includes bibliographical references (pages 41-45).
  - Faculty development and evaluation in higher education Albert B. Smith; prepared by the ERIC Clearinghouse on Higher Education, the George Washington University., 1976; Series 6; 76 pages; 23 cm. (Box 2, Folder 11)
    Includes bibliographical references (pages 71-76).
  - Accreditation and institutional eligibility David A. Trivett; prepared by the ERIC Clearinghouse on Higher Education, the George Washington University., 1976; Series 6; 96 pages; 23 cm. (Box 2, Folder 11)
    Includes bibliographical references (pages 89-96).; Also issued online.
  - Student rights, decisionmaking, and the law Terrence N. Tice; prepared by the ERIC Clearinghouse on Higher Education, George Washington University., 1976; Series 6; 98 pages; 23 cm. (Box 2, Folder 11)
    Includes bibliographical references (pages 48-88) and indexes.; Index of names. -- Index of subjects. -- Table of cases.; Prepared pursuant to a contract with the National Institute of Education, U.S. Department of Health, Education and Welfare.
  - Federal regulation and higher education Louis W. Bender; prepared by the ERIC Clearinghouse on Higher Education, George Washington University., 1977; Series 6; 79 pages; 23 cm. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    Includes bibliographical references (pages 74-79).
  - Institutional goals and student costs George B. Weathersby and Frederic Jacobs; prepared by the ERIC Clearinghouse on Higher Education, George Washington University., 1977; Series 6; 48 pages: illustrations; 23 cm. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    Includes bibliographical references (pages 42-48).
  - Higher education opportunity: a decade of progress Larry L. Leslie; prepared by the ERIC Clearinghouse on Higher Education, the George Washington University., 1977; Series 6; 57, 18 pages: graphs; 23 cm. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    Prepared by the ERIC Clearinghouse on Higher Education, George Washington University.; Includes bibliographical references (pages 54-57).
  - Quantitative approaches to higher education management: potential, limits, and challenge G. Ben Lawrence and Allan L. Service, editors; prepared by the ERIC Clearinghouse on Higher Education, George Washington University., 1977; Series 6; 91 pages; 23 cm. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    Prepared by the ERIC Clearinghouse on Higher Education at George Washington University.; Includes bibliographical references (pages 81-91).
  - University admissions: dilemmas and potential Carol Herrnstadt Shulman; prepared by the ERIC Clearinghouse on Higher Education, the George Washington University., 1977; Series 6; 52 pages; 23 cm. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    Includes bibliographical references (pages 46-52).
  - Alternative tuition systems Douglas S. MacDonald; prepared by the ERIC Clearinghouse on Higher Education, George Washington University, Washington, D.C., 1978; Series 6; 44 pages; 23 cm. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    Includes bibliographical references (pages 39-44).
  - Concepts of career and general education by Paul A. Olson., 1977; Series 6; 41 pages; 23 cm. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    Prepared by the ERIC Clearinghouse on Higher Education, George Washington University, pursuant to a contract with the National Institute of Education, U.S. Dept. of Health, Education and Welfare.; Includes bibliographical references.
  - To improve instruction Charles C. Cole, Jr.; prepared by the ERIC Clearinghouse on Higher Education, the George Washington University., 1978; Series 6; 80 pages; 23 cm. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    Includes bibliographical references (pages 66-80).; Also issued online.
- Population Studies, Series 7
  - The Control of Incinerator-Caused Air Pollution in New York City: 1946-1965, 1968-03-01; Series 7 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Pricing and efficiency in water resource management by Robert K. Davis and Steve H. Hanke; [prepared for National Water Commission]., 1971-12-01; Series 7; 1 volume (various pagings): illustrations; 28 cm (Box 1, Folder 2)
    "December, 1971."; "Departments of Geography &amp Environmental Engineering and Political Economy, Johns Hopkins University."; "Natural Resources Policy Center, the George Washington University."; "NTIS: PB 209083."; "NWC-SBS-72-044."; Includes bibliographical references.; NWC 71-022.
  - Analytical review of research reports on the social impacts of water resources development projects: final report to Institute for Water Resources, U.S. Army Corps of Engineers under purchase order DACW 72-78-M-0290 by Henry H. Hitchcock, principal investigator; R. Chester Strobel, research assistant., 1977-03-01; Series 7; approximately 550 pages; 28 cm (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Analytical Review of Research Reports on the Social Impacts of Water Resources Development Projects, 1978-11-01; Series 7 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - A Workbook on Alternative Future Life Styles Related to Energy Demands, 1973-08-01; Series 7 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Energy implications of an aging population by Ali B. Cambel, Carol J. DeVita, George A. Heffernan., 1979-12-01; Series 7; iii, 69 pages: graphs; 28 cm (Box 1, Folder 6)
    "HCP-4040-3."; Prepared for the U.S. Dept. of Energy, Satellite Power System Project Office under grant numbers EG-77-G-01-4040.; Includes bibliographical references (pages 68-69).
  - [Proceedings of the] Energy, Environment and Ethics Seminar presented by George Washington University, Continuing Engineering Education Program and National Association of Environmental Professionals, held at the Shoreham Americana Hotel, Washington, D.C., November 5-7, 1975., 1975-11-01; Series 7; 327 pages in various pagings; 28 cm (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - The potential for small-scale, decentralized energy sources and the federal role in their development by Denis Hayes., 1978-02-01; Series 7; v, 43 leaves; 28 cm (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Preface by Albert H. Teich, seminar project director.; Seminar conducted under grant number EE-77-G-05-5618 from the U.S. Dept. of Energy.; This paper has been prepared from a tape recording of a presentation and discussion at an Energy Policy Seminar conducted by George Washington University's Graduate Program in Science, Technology and Public Policy, February 1, 1978.
  - Energy R and D: U.S. technology transfer to advanced western countries by James P. Lester., 1975-11-01; Series 7; vi, 77 leaves; 28 cm (Box 1, Folder 9)
    "Report of a case study carried out under NSF Grant ST-44205, 'Technology transfer and U.S. foreign policy.'"; Cover title.; Includes bibliographical references (leaves 70-77).
  - Definition study for a net energy assessment: the Washington, D.C. Metrorail System prepared for ERDA under P.O. 76-34 by the George Washington University Program of Policy Studies in Science and Technology; Vary T. Coates, principal investigator; Robert W. Anthony, project manager., 1976-10-01; Series 7; 2 volumes: illustrations; 28 cm (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Includes bibliographical references (volume 1, leaves 62-66).; volume 2. Appendices.
  - Appendices to Definition Study for a Net Energy Assessment: The Washington, D.C. Metrorail System, 1976-10-01; Series 7 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Utility rate structures and distributed thermal energy storage: a cost benefit analysis: basic research report for period October 1978-February 1979 by Evan F. Koenig; conducted under the direction of Ali B. Cambel., 1979-02-01; Series 7; iv, 38 leaves; 28 cm (Box 1, Folder 11)
    "HCP/3411-1."; Prepared for the U.S. Dept. of Energy, Energy Storage Division under special research support agreement ET-78-S-01-3411.; Includes bibliographical references (leaf 31).
  - Mathematical structure of the international coal trade model by James E. Falk, Garth P. McCormick., 1982-09-01; Series 7; v, 59 leaves: illustrations; 28 cm (Box 1, Folder 12)
    "30 September 1982."; Cover title.; Includes bibliographical references (leaf 59).; Final report.; Sponsored by Oak Ridge National Laboratories, contract 19X-22204C.
  - Historical, current and projected trends in private sector RD and D investment in oil shale and coal liquefaction technologies by Peter Huessy., 1982-05-01; Series 7; 38 leaves; 28 cm (Box 1, Folder 13)
    "May 1982."; "Report to the National Science Foundation, Division of Policy Research and Analysis, P.O. no. 43877."
  - Basic research foundations for public education programs in energy conservation Joseph B. Margolin, Marion Ruth Misch (Behavioral Studies Group); contributors, Saul Barry Wax, Nathan Maccoby, Robert B. Cialdini., 1980-09-01; Series 7; 570 pages in various pagings: illustrations; 28 cm (Box 1, Folder 14)
    "September 1980."; Includes bibliographical references.; Prepared for the U.S. Department of Energy under contract EM78-Sol-5256.
  - Nuclear technology and the fabric of government, by Harold P. Green., 1965-01-01; Series 7; v, 41 pages 28 cm. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - The joint committee on atomic energy: a model for legislative reform?, 1964-12-01; Series 7; v, 15 pages. (Box 1, Folder 15)
    This article apperared originally in 32 George Washington Law Review, No. 5, June 1964.; Includes bibliographical references.
  - The social control of technology: the problem of nuclear industry by John W. Snow., 1968-11-01; Series 7; 39 pages: illustrations; 29 cm. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - The Joint Committee on Atomic Energy: a study in fusion of governmental power; report by Harold P. Green, Director; Alan Rosenthal, Associate Director., 1961; Series 7; ii, 338 pages: illustrations; 28 cm (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - The exploration ethic: its historical-intellectual basis: final project report by Program of Policy Studies in Science and Technology., 1975-06-01; Series 7; 394 leaves in various foliations; 28 cm (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Final report submitted to NASA-Goddard Space Flight Center under Contract NAS5-20843 by the Program of Policy Studies in Science and Technology of George Washington University.; Includes bibliographical references (pages 15-1-15-35).; part 1. Priscoli, J.D. and Hitchcock, H.H. Historical documentation.--pt. 2. Marney, M. Intellectual basis.
  - Final report for microwave sensing of snowpack wetness prepared by Roger H. Lang for National Aeronautics and Space Administration, Goodard [sic] Space Flight Center., 1979-01-01; Series 7; 26 leaves: illustrations; 30 cm (Box 1, Folder 18)
    "January 31, 1979."; Work performed under contract NAS-S-23809.; Includes bibliographical references (leaves 25-26).
  - The effect of relevant emotional content on performance and learning in programmed instruction [by] Lawrence E. Schlesinger, Edward H. Fischer, and Stanley L. Cohen. Final report to Media Research and Dissemination Branch, Office of Education, Title VII, grant number 7-18-0100-197., 1965-02-01; Series 7; 48, [3] leaves 28 cm (Box 1, Folder 19)
    Includes bibliographical references (leaves 49-50).
  - A handbook for programmers of automated instruction by William H. Melching [and others]., 1963-09-01; Series 7; iv, 164, 33 pages: illustrations; 27 cm (Box 1, Folder 19)
    "Under the technical supervision of the George Washington University Human Resources Research Office operating under contract with the Department of the Army"--Cover.; Includes bibliographical references (pages 163-164).
  - Final report, Exxon Foundation grant EXPER SIM at the George Washington University by Salvatore R. Paratore, project director., 1977; Series 7; 119 leaves in various foliations: illustrations; 29 cm (Box 1, Folder 20)
    Cover title.; Work performed under Grant 728-430, Exxon Foundation.; Includes bibliographical references.; EXPER SIM review.--GWU EXPER SIM manual.--Budget summary.--Student evaluation.--Implementation history.
  - Planning and programming in the Soil Conservation Service., 1972-06-01; Series 7; 27 pages. (Box 2, Folder 1)
    [Prepared for Seminar 3 ... on Technology assessment methodology."
  - Homeowner's Title Registration Corporation: a program to reduce the land-related costs of housing. A report prepared by Program of Policy Studies in Science and Technology, the George Washington University, Washington, D.C., 1972-02-01; Series 7; 4 volumes; 28 cm (Box 2, Folder 2)
    Prepared for Dept. of Housing and Urban Development, under contract H-1369.; Includes bibliographical references.
  - Homeowner's Title Registration Corporation: A Program to Reduce the Land-Related Costs of Housing Vol. 2, 1972-02-01; Series 7; 4 volumes; 28 cm (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Homeowner's Title Registration Corporation: A Program to Reduce the Land-Related Costs of Housing Vol. 3, 1972-02-01; Series 7; 4 volumes; 28 cm (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Homeowner's Title Registration Corporation: A Program to Reduce the Land-Related Costs of Housing Vol. 4, 1972-02-01; Series 7; 4 volumes; 28 cm (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Research, innovation, and economic change: policy options for Congressional consideration prepared for Special Study on Economic Change, Joint Economic Committee, U.S. Congress; by John M. Logsdon., 1979-08-01; Series 7; 64, 17 leaves; 29 cm (Box 2, Folder 6)
    Outgrowth of a workshop held in December, 1978 at George Washington University.; Includes bibliographical references.
  - Santa Clara County, California: a study of the local impacts of research and research-based manufacturing by George Washington University., 1966-01-01; Series 7; 174 leaves: illustrations; 28 cm (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - The effect of changing patterns and levels of federal research and development funding on industry: final report by Guy Black., 1973-07-01; Series 7; xiii, 423, [26] leaves; 28 cm (Box 2, Folder 8)
    "Prepared for The National Science Foundation under Grant GR-102."; Appendix F: Thinking about research and development. (Brochure).
  - The new technological era: a view from the law., 1968-01-01; Series 7; ii, 9 pages; 28 cm. (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Seminar on social change in the American value system: proceedings by George Washington University, 18 November, 1967., 1967-11-01; Series 7; iv, 71 pages; 28 cm. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    Moderator and list of attendees.--"Change, Social Problems, and Political Tensions in American Society," by Seymour Martin Lipset.--Critique and commentary, by John P. Roche.--Discussion.
  - Historical aspects of technology assessment., 1969-08-01; Series 7; 21 pages. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    Paper presented at the Engineering Foundation Research Conference, Andover, N.H., Aug. 1969.
  - The law's interface with expanding technology., 1972-08-01; Series 7; 13 pages 28 cm. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    "Paper presented to a joint symposium entitled Technology Assessment: a Future-Oriented Policy Tool."
  - Genetic technology: promises and problems, by Mark S. Frankel., 1973-03-01; Series 7; ix, 93 pages 28 cm. (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Research, development and financial performance by Guy Black and William A. Fischer., 1974-05-01; Series 7; iii, 32 pages; 28 cm. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    "This paper summarizes part of a study funded by a grant from the National Science Foundation."; Includes bibliographical references (page 27).
  - Research, development and business conditions, 1960-71 by Guy Black., 1974-05-01; Series 7; iii, 30 pages; 28 cm. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    "This paper summarizes part of a study funded by a grant from the National Science Foundation."
  - The sensitivity of types of research and development to business conditions by Guy Black., 1974-05-01; Series 7; iii, 24 pages; 28 cm. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    "This paper summarizes part of a study funded by a grant from the National Science Foundation."; Includes bibliographical references (page 20).
  - Systems approaches to multi-variable socioeconomic problems: an appraisal., 1968-08-01; Series 7; 47 pages. (Box 2, Folder 10)
    NTIS. PB 182 871.
  - The systems approach and the urban dilemma., 1968-07-01; Series 7; 45 pages. (Box 2, Folder 10)
    Includes bibliographical references (page 45).
  - The Human Design, 1965-01-01; Series 7; 10 pages; 27 cm (Box 2, Folder 10)
    Program of Policy Studies in Science and Technology. Paper, numbers 6.; Reprinted from journal of individual psychology, volume 20, Nov. 1964.
  - Science and technology in the theories of social and political alienation., 1969-06-01; Series 7; 65 pages 28 cm. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - What's happening to small business research and development? by Guy Black., 1971-05-01; Series 7; 13 pages; 28 cm. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Financial variables associated with R &amp D expenditures by industry., 1968-01-01; Series 7; 12 p. 28 cm. (Box 2, Folder 10)
    Cover title.; References: inside back cover.
  - Some effects of Federal procurement of research and development on industry by Guy Black., 1968-07-01; Series 7; 70 pages: illustrations; 28 cm. (Box 2, Folder 10)
    "July 1968."; "This proposal is based in part on research funded by the National Science Foundation."; Includes bibliographical references (pages 69-70).
  - Critical review of the Marine Science Commission Report; proceedings of a Seminar held by the Marine Technology Society Law Committee in conjunction with the George Washington University, Washington, D.C. [on] January 31, 1969., 1969-01-01; Series 7; 94 pages 22 cm (Box 2, Folder 10)
    Proceedings of a symposium which was designated to evaluate the salient features of Our Nation and the Sea, the report of the Commission on Marine Science, Engineering and Resources.
  - Manpower policies for the use of science and technology in development by Charles V. Kidd., 1978-10-01; Series 7; iv, 255, [9] pages; 29 cm (Box 2, Folder 11)
    "A background paper for the United States delegation to the UN Conference on Science and Technology for Development."; Prepublication copy.; Work supported by National Science Foundation under Grant No. INT 78-08297.; Includes bibliographical references (pages 256-264).
  - Trends in state and federal land use law relating to inventories, monitoring and evaluation prepared for the Office of User Affairs, National Aeronautics and Space Administration, by Charles M. Lamb., 1974-03-01; Series 7; iv, 82 pages; 28 cm (Box 2, Folder 11)
    Includes bibliographical references.; Photocopy.
  - Final report of analysis of the need for and feasibility of more effective distribution of government-supported non-written material by Educational Policy Group, Program of Policy Studies in Science and Technology; Joseph B. Margolin, principal investigator., 1970-04-01; Series 7; 286 pages; 28 cm (Box 2, Folder 12)
    Cover title.; Work done under contract OEC 000716 4457(016).; Includes bibliographical references (pages 275-286).
  - Determinants of recreational use at eight Corps of Engineers reservoirs in the Dallas-Fort Worth area by Mary A. Holman., 1970; Series 7; vii, 115, A-79 leaves; 28 cm (Box 2, Folder 13)
    Information provided mostly by the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers.; Project financially supported by Resources for the Future, Incorporated.; Includes bibliographical references.
  - Shoreline recreation resources of the United States: report to the Outdoor Recreation Resources Review Commission by the George Washington University., 1962; Series 7; viii, 156 pages: illustrations, maps; 26 cm. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    Includes bibliographical references.; Also issued via the World Wide Web.
  - Planning and programming in natural resources management: papers and panel reports of the First Executive Seminar in Natural Resources Policy, Harpers Ferry, West Va., June 3-10, 1966 by Center for Natural Resources Policy Studies, George Washington University., 1966-06-01; Series 7; ix, 69 leaves; 28 cm (Box 2, Folder 15)
    " ... seminar sponsored jointly by the Center for Natural Resources Policy Studies of the George Washington University and the United States Department of the Interior."
  - Toward the "techno-corporate" state: an essay in American constitutionalism by Arthur S. Miller., 1968; Series 7; 73 pages; 25 cm. (Box 3, Folder 1)
    "Reprinted by permission of the Author from the Villanova Law Review, Volume 14, No. l, Fall 1968."; Cover title.; Includes bibliographical references.
  - Corporate gigantism and "technological imperatives " by Arthur Selwyn Miller., 1969; Series 7; [55] pages; 23 cm. (Box 3, Folder 1)
    "Reprinted by permission from The Emory University Law School Journal of Public Law, Volume 18, No. 2."; Cover title.; Includes bibliographical references.
  - Specifications by Ronald Gary Schumann., 1980; Series 7; 102 pages; 23 cm. (Box 3, Folder 1)
    Revision of the author's thesis (LL. M., George Washington University).